<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-11T23:12:03+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jack Taylor</title><subtitle>Built with Jekyll, hosted on Github Pages.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">3D Printing for the NHS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/05/11/3dprinting-covid.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3D Printing for the NHS" /><published>2020-05-11T20:29:51+01:00</published><updated>2020-05-11T20:29:51+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/05/11/3dprinting-covid</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/05/11/3dprinting-covid.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve followed the development of 3D printing fairly closely over the past few years, but grew interested enough in it in 2019 to make it a part of my undergraduate dissertation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Computer Vision tools, I used a model based approach to recreate a human head, so that it could be 3D printed. I’ll spare you most of the detail, but it didn’t work very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../../resources/3dheadprint.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;covid19-and-ppe&quot;&gt;Covid–19 and PPE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the astonishing lack of preparedness on the part of the UK government first became aware to me I wasn’t surprised. I’ve been a &lt;em&gt;Raving Momentum Stalinist Trotskyist Corbynite Marxist Thug&lt;/em&gt; for the past few years, so I’m all too aware of the Conservative government’s lack of shits regarding the health service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, frontline healthcare staff didn’t have enough masks, face shields, or scrubs. The ones they did have were out of date, often by years. The government then &lt;em&gt;chose&lt;/em&gt; not to opt into a massive Europe wide operation to procure PPE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to help, and as luck would have it a video popped up in my Facebook  news feed. A local man was using his 3D printers to manufacture face shields, I got in touch, and then ordered my own printer and some filament, how hard could it be to get started?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../../resources/printer-assembly.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Assembling the printer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered a Creality Ender-5, and got to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were some teething problems…
&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../../resources/printerhotend.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Teething problems&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bed levelling procedure took a while to master, but with that done I was off to the races! (Not Cheltenham)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;face-shields&quot;&gt;Face Shields&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most useful thing I could produce was face shields. I could print a disposable headband in around 20 minutes, to which I would staple a sheet of acrylic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These seemed great in theory, but after some provisioinal feedback from the ambulance service, stating they would fall apart in a small breeze, we moved onto more structurally sound designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../../resources/orange-white-production.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Disposables&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following design is what has been come to known as a Verkstan, after the &lt;a href=&quot;https://3dverkstan.se&quot;&gt;Swedish 3D printing firm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../../resources/blueproduction.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Verkstan Visor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are &lt;strong&gt;far&lt;/strong&gt; better than the disposable design, and have recieved much better feedback from frontline healthcare staff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently producing around 10 of these a day. It’s a drop in the ocean compared to what’s required, but I know it’s helping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mutual-aid&quot;&gt;Mutual Aid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t do this alone, and since the beginning have been part of a maker community that is now also producing scrubs and face masks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all being distributed for free to those who need it through our online portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fin&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;fin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve really rushed this post, and it probably makes no sense, but wanted to fill up the white space on my blog hompage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoyed it, solidarity forever.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Background</summary></entry></feed>